this week's blog post is called
transparency we are open sourcing the
entire company and then the world a lot
of inefficiencies that exists in our
current system comes about due to a lack
of transparency our governments spend a
lot of money and time coming up with
solutions and then they need to sell
those very solutions back to their
constituents because they were not
designed transparently corporations
safeguard their proprietary information
so the competition will not get it then
they must counteract this lack of
transparency with expensive advertising
to offset some of the Trust's that they
have lost our global cooperative is
going to be as transparent as possible
as transparent as our current technology
allows as we create the technology to be
ever more transparent eventually all
information that is available to the
Board of Directors will be available to
every single member in an organized and
easily understood way our finances will
be transparent that is where funding
comes from and where and how it is spent
will be available to all members during
and after our first crowdfunding
campaign this level of transparency
helps in many ways it makes us more
efficient more trustworthy and protects
us from many of the ways we could be
destroyed our for-profit competition
cannot be this transparent and therefore
cannot compete with our cooperative it
makes us more efficient because ideas on
how to improve or mitigate risk can come
from anywhere and everywhere when we
fail at anything we will have an open
and honest conversation and come up with
ideas on how to improve this in the
future so it does not happen again for
example if we have been in existence
during the financial crash of 2008 and
some of our members were able to foresee
this issue and we did not listen to them
and so we had the negative effect from
the financial crash we could look back
with hindsight and ask why didn't we
listen to those exact people and is
there a way to make sure those ideas are
listened to and and heard in the future
before the next financial crash or the
next bubble bursts mistakes made openly
lead to faster improvements we are not
silencing dissent we are encouraging it
and
to make our entire system better this is
what transparency does as a corporation
when we make mistakes we will have to
own them in full public view so that
everyone can see what happened suggest
why it happened and create a system to
make it less likely to happen in the
future to facilitate this we need an
internal culture that allows mistakes
and encourages learning from them we are
going to fail in the right direction as
we perfect the system
spoiler alert there will never be
perfect we are using full transparency
internally but we are also creating
systems to create more transparency in
the external world as well as consumers
we will demand transparency from
companies we support and those that
cannot exist within this transparency
will go out of business as voters we
will demand transparency from our
politicians so we can better understand
the decisions they are making and why
the only way to compete with
transparency is to become more
transparent yourself if you cannot exist
in a system of transparency you will
probably no longer exist when
information is organized and made
accessible to everyone a whole new level
of transparency is possible because when
we see it as possible we will demand it
transparency neutralizes marketing you
cannot create a brand that operates on
spin of a product when we have access to
the truth it does not matter if you say
your product is environmentally-friendly
and put on a green label because we can
see the ingredients and track the record
of the company and easily compare it to
the other competing products corrupt
politicians cannot remain in power when
we can monitor their platform they were
selected on and track the promises kept
or broken when we create a system to
keep data on our politicians lobbyists
lose most of the power that was obtained
in secret pharmaceutical companies in
the healthcare industry cannot get away
with harming or poisoning us because it
makes more profit than they have to pay
out in lawsuits when we can
transparently see those lawsuits and
stand behind our fellow fellow consumers
it becomes financially risky to be evil
in a transparent system we are going to
run our board of directors
with full transparency the board meets
weekly for an hour and these meetings
are broadcast live to our numbers
members will be able to offer
suggestions give opinions and
participate as much as the current
technology allows members can vote
directly on issues or delegate their
vote to members of the board to vote on
their behalf all members are able to
participate at any level they desire
they can watch and participate directly
in board meetings when the technology
allows they can access and understand
all relative information to help make
informed decisions the people who are
very involved and become well known by
our members will naturally become the
next new board members and so the
transition to the board will be a much
more seamless this is efficiency of
transparency at work no secret we liens
and dealings can be done behind the
members backs as all internal corporate
decisions must be made in full public
view example if the government demands
we make internal data available to them
the board has to tell the membership as
every piece of information available to
the board is available to all members by
design the level of trust that is
generated with transparency cannot be
replicated without it because every
member can go as deep into the
information as they wish to they can
also trust the surface level information
made available in an easy-to-understand
format they know anyone can access the
information so someone who understands
it and cares will so we can trust any
issue or corruption will come to light
the company is designed so that the
newest member can trust the system that
was put in place before they arrived
because they can fully see the entire
process transparency in for-profit
corporations could mean somebody steals
your proprietary idea and brings it to
market before you working in complete
cooperation we do not have this problem
as nobody can steal and recreate our
idea in secret we can operate with full
transparency because we are not in
competition with the existing companies
but are in cooperation with each other
Facebook cannot operate transparently so
that we can trust them and therefore
they cannot recreate what we will create
we however
and reproduce a facebook like platform
that we designed for the purpose of
connection and information with full
transparency out in the open for
everyone to see because the worst that
happens if somebody does it first what
do we do if a different company creates
a member owned fully democratic
transparent technology company where
everybody is invited and we solve
problems together using the tech we
create we join them now or in the future
even our competition isn't actually
competition because the design fixes it
the only people who would actually be
competition are people doing the exact
same thing in which case we join them
just like they could join us the reason
not to have transparency is to hide
something from your members customers
shareholders or the government we have
nothing to hide so the outside forces
cannot create spin about what we could
be up to because we are doing it in full
view for everyone to see full
transparency helps us problem-solve more
efficiently the Board of Directors is
acting as the greater memberships proxy
for instance if the Board of Directors
makes a budget and then goes over it it
is not only the Board of Directors that
are responsible as every single member
had access to the budget and could have
improved it if they had better ideas
because of this it is a lot easier to go
back to the membership and ask for more
money since we all went over-budget
together
similarly if there is a legal
ramification from a decision that is
made we are all equally liable if our
data is breached in a way that nobody
foresaw or in a way that we deemed it
was an allowable risk then we are all
equally liable this does not mean we do
not make these issues right when
mistakes happen it means that they are
less likely to occur and when they do
they are less likely to have a large
settlement amount attached to them it is
like the difference between suing a
restaurant that gave you food poisoning
versus suing a friend who cooked you
dinner and gave you food poisoning
the former is expected and the latter
makes you a bad friend we take the
entire risk together transparency is the
key to this revolution
it gives us the ability to trust it
makes us efficient and it gives us the
potential to be as involved as we desire
thank you please like and subscribe as
we are creating the global cooperative
that is going to create an abundant and
peaceful world for every single human
being who wants to be a part of it take
care